Preliminary Guide to the American Economic Association Records, 1886-2008 and undated RL.00033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0118)
  - Secretary-Treasurer Files, 1949-1980s; 1
    - Asia Foundation, 1984 (Box 972)
    - Association of American Colleges, 1979 (Box 972)
      Includes correspondence on proposed joint statement to Congress on basic research
    - Association of American Publishers, 1976 (Box 972)
    - Economic History Association, 1982-1983 (Box 972)
    - Economics Institute, 1976-1982; 3 folders (Box 972)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1976-1983 (Box 972)
      Includes correspondence congratulating Association members elected to Academy
    - American Association of Junior Colleges, 1970-1972 (Box 972)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1968-1979 (Box 972)
      Includes AAUP documents and publications
    - American Meteorological Society, 1980-1981 (Box 972)
      Includes correspondence about cosponsoring a symposium
    - American Political Science Association, 1971-1984 (Box 972)
      Includes routine inter-society correspondence
    - American Psychological Association, 1983 (Box 972)
    - American Sociological Association, 1982-1984 (Box 972)
    - American Statistical Association, 1971-1983 (Box 972)
    - Relationships with Other Associations, 1972-1984 (Box 973)
    - Fritz Machlup, 1976-1977 (Box 973)
      Includes correspondence about references and databasing information
    - Walter W. Heller, 1974 (Box 973)
      Includes files related to role as past-president of the AEA
    - Robert Aaron Gordon, 1975 (Box 973)
    - Franco Modigliani, 1976 (Box 973)
    - Lawrence R. Klein, 1977 (Box 973)
    - Jacob Marshak, 1978 (Box 973)
    - Tjalling C. Koopmans, 1978 (Box 973)
    - Archives, 1971-1982 (Box 973)
      Includes correspondence about materials in Association archives
    - Directory of Members, 1978; 3 folders (Box 973)
      Includes correspondence about directory and questionnaire
    - Data from 1978 Directory Questionnaire, 2 folders (Box 974)
      Includes printouts of data
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 974)
      Includes AEA correspondence regarding meetings in states that had not ratified the Equal Rights Amendment
    - National Archives Advisory Council, 1968-1983 (Box 974)
      Includes correspondence about AEA representatives to council
    - Joint Committee with Association of American Law Schools, 1970-1977 (Box 974)
      Includes inter-society correspondence
    - Ad Hoc Committee to Consider and Recommend Center Activities, 1980 (Box 975)
    - UNESCO, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 975)
      Includes correspondence about AEA representatives to UNESCO
    - Policy Board of the Journal of Consumer Research, 1978-1983 (Box 975)
      Includes correspondence about AEA representatives
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1971-1980; 2 folders (Box 975)
    - International Economic Association, 1977-1980; 5 folders (Box 975)
    - Walter J. Johnson, 1962-1964 (Box 975)
      Includes correspondence about publishing AEA journals
    - International Economic Association, 1972-1978; 4 folders (Box 976)
    - Committee on Economic Education, 1968-1980; 4 folders (Box 976)
    - Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), 1972-1981; 6 folders (Box 977)
      Includes correspondence, newsletters, and roster of women economists
    - Economics Institute, 1975-1976; 5 folders (Box 977)
    - Committee on Political Discrimination, 1974-1981; 20 folders (Box 978)
      Includes correspondence about studying political discrimination in the economics profession
    - Committee on Political Discrimination, 1973-1980; 9 folders (Box 979)
    - Oversize Folder 1, 1949 (Oversize-folder 1)
      Includes photograph of lunch session from 1949 AEA meeting featuring Paul Douglas as the lunch speaker
  - AEA office files and Executive Committee records
    - AEA Executive Committee, 1969-1982 (Box 981-986)
  - American Economic Association, Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), 1971-1996
    - Historical data files, 1971-1974 (Box 987)
    - Historical data subject files, 1972-1974 (Box 988)
      Includes correspondence from other economic associations; committee business and future; Ford Foundation funding proposal (1973); correspondence regarding discrimination cases (Edna Maynard Gott); and hiring practices committee.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 989)
      Includes questionnaires.
    - Roster and correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 990)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 991)
    - 1975 conference at Wellesley College and 1974 survey (Box 992)
      Includes Wellesley Center for the Study of Women in Higher Education and the Professions.
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 993)
    - Budget and CSWEP committee reports, 1972-1977 (Box 994)
    - CSWEP reports, 1973-1976 (Box 995)
      Includes reports by Sonia Pressman, Sonia P. Fuentes, George J. Stigler, Elizabeth Clayton, David M. Gordon, the Boulding-Treagar Report in the AER, and various CSWEP reports.
    - CSWEP meetings at Wellesley College and in New York, San Francisco, Washington, DC, and Atlantic City, 1973-1977 (Box 996)
    - Meetings and reports, minutes and correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 997)
    - Meetings and reports, proposals for CSWEP sessions at AEA meetings, 1974-1987 (Box 998)
    - Correspondence and annual reports, 1980-1987 (Box 999)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1000)
    - Annual report and meetings, 1988-1989 (Box 1001)
    - Meetings, 1989-1992 (Box 1002)
      Includes CSWEP sessions.
    - Board members, meetings, and meeting minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 1003)
    - Board meetings and meeting minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 1004)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1005)
    - Budget, 1984-1991 (Box 1006)
    - Miscellaneous subject files, A-R, 1974-1988 (Box 1007)
      Includes information on careers for women and careers for women in economics; financial aid; newsletter editorial policy; Federation of Organizations for Professional Women (FOPW); National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER); National Science Foundation (NSF); New York Women Economists; questionnaire results (1974-1989); and research project on women Ph.D. economists, data, proposal, correspondence (1986-1988).
    - Miscellaneous subject files, R-W; membership data, 1981-1989 (Box 1008)
      Includes rosters (1983, 1985, 1987); Roster of Women in Agricultural Economics (1984); correspondence regarding salaries; textbook project; and membership data (1981-1985, including floppy disks 014-015).
    - Membership data, 1985-1987 (Box 1009)
    - Abstracts for papers, 1987-1992 (Box 1010)
    - Newsletters, 1972-1984 (Box 1011)
      Includes newsletter issues and job opportunities.
    - Newsletters, 1985-1987 (Box 1012)
      Includes newsletter issues, correspondence, and articles and clippings for inclusion in newsletter.
    - Newsletters, 1988-1991 (Box 1013)
    - Newsletters, 1991-1992 Winter (Box 1014)
      Includes floppy disk 010, Winter 1992.
    - Newsletters, 1992 Spring-1993 Spring/Summer (Box 1015)
      Includes floppy disks 001 (newsletter labels, 1992), 012 (Spring 1992), 009 (Fall 1992), 005-006 (Spring 1993).
    - Newsletters, miscellaneous, 1977-1991 and undated (Box 1016-1017)
      Includes floppy disk 013 (undated).
    - CSWEP meetings and meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, and other office files, 1989-1991 (Box 1018)
      Includes CSWEP sessions at AEA meetings.
    - CSWEP Meetings and meeting minutes, reports and annual reports, correspondence, and other office files, 1991-1992 (Box 1019-1020)
      Includes CSWEP sessions at AEA meetings and floppy disks 011 (1992), 008 (1991 June 19-1992 Jan. 16), 007 (1992 Jan. 16-1992 May 14), and 004 (1992 May 15-1992 Dec. 21).
    - CSWEP Meetings and meeting minutes, reports and annual reports, correspondence, and other office files, 1993 (Box 1021)
      Includes CSWEP sessions at AEA meetings and floppy disks 003 (1992 Dec. 21-1993 Mar. 26) and 002 (1993 March 26).
    - Published books and reports on women and education and occupations, 1973-1987 (Box 1022)
    - R. Blank CSWEP materials, 1994-1996 (Box 1023-1024)
  - AEA Financial Records, 1962-1988
    - Accounts Receivable
      - Cash receipts, 1970-1981 (Box 1025-1030)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962-1970 (Box 1031-1033)
    - Guide sales, 1965-1969 (Box 1034-1035)
    - Cash disbursements, 1957-1987 (Box 1036-1039)
    - Payroll records, 1951-1988 (Box 1040-1049)
    - General ledger books, 1963-1987 (Box 1050-1053)
    - Audit, investment, and project ledgers, 1958-1969 (Box 1054)
  - Member cards, microfilm, and photographs
    - Member cards, 1900-1975 (Box 1055-1125)
    - Microfilm, 48 rolls (Box 1126-1128)
      Includes AER vols. 40-65 and vols. 68-70; JEL vols. 8-13 and 16-18; JE Abstracts vols. 2-6; ACLS Parts 1 and 2 (2 rolls each); and JE Perspectives, vol. 2.
    - Photographs (Box 1129)
  - Oversize materials
    - Black-and-white photograph of a group taken at an unidentified meeting, undated, (39"x10") (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2001-0082)
  Addition (2001-0082) (4000 items, 9.6 linear feet; dated 1998-1999) includes records for the American Economic Review, including correspondence and referee files for rejected and withdrawn articles (1998), accepted articles (1999), and papers and proceedings (1999).
  - AER Rejects, A-B, 1998 (Box 1)
  - AER Rejects, B-D, 1998 (Box 2)
  - AER Rejects, D-H, 1998 (Box 3)
  - AER Rejects, H-L, 1998 (Box 4)
  - AER Rejects, L-N, 1998 (Box 5)
  - AER Rejects, N-R, 1998 (Box 6)
  - AER Rejects, R-S, and Withdrawn, 1998 (Box 7)
  - AER Rejects, T-W, and Withdrawn, 1998 (Box 8)
  - AER Rejects, T-V, 1998 (Box 9)
  - AER Acceptances, 1999 March (Box 9-10)
  - AER Papers and Proceedings, 1999 May (Box 10-11)
  - AER Acceptances, 1999 June (Box 12-13)
  - AER Acceptances, 1999 September (Box 13-15)
  - AER Acceptances, 1999 December (Box 15-16)
- Accession (2002-0215)
  Addition (2002-0215) (21000 items, 33.4 linear feet; dated 1999-2001) contains Records for the American Economic Review, including editorial correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts for rejected articles (1999-2000) and accepted articles (March-December 2001) and papers and proceedings (2000-2001). There are also 37 electronic documents on one floppy disk. The electronic documents have been transferred to the electronic records server.
  - AER Rejects, A-B, 1999 (Box 1)
  - AER Rejects, B-C, 1999 (Box 2)
  - AER Rejects, C-F, 1999 (Box 3)
  - AER Rejects, G-H, 1999 (Box 4)
  - AER Rejects, H-K, 1999 (Box 5)
  - AER Rejects, K-M, 1999 (Box 6)
  - AER Rejects, M-O, 1999 (Box 7)
  - AER Rejects, O-R, 1999 (Box 8)
  - AER Rejects, R-S, 1999 (Box 9)
  - AER Rejects, S-W, 1999 (Box 10)
  - AER Rejects, W-Z, 1999 (Box 11)
  - AER Rejects, A, 2000 (Box 11)
  - AER Rejects, A, 2000 (Box 12)
  - AER Rejects, A-B, 2000 (Box 13)
  - AER Rejects, B, 2000 (Box 14)
  - AER Rejects, B-C, 2000 (Box 15)
  - AER Rejects, C, 2000 (Box 16-17)
  - AER Rejects, C-D, 2000 (Box 18)
  - AER Rejects, D-E, 2000 (Box 19)
  - AER Rejects, E-F, 2000 (Box 20)
  - AER Rejects, F-G, 2000 (Box 21)
  - AER Rejects, G, 2000 (Box 22)
  - AER Rejects, G-H, 2000 (Box 23)
  - AER Rejects, H, 2000 (Box 24)
  - AER Rejects, H-I, 2000 (Box 25)
  - AER Rejects, I-K, 2000 (Box 26)
  - AER Rejects, K, 2000 (Box 27)
  - AER Rejects, K-L, 2000 (Box 28)
  - AER Rejects, L, 2000 (Box 29)
  - AER Rejects, L-M, 2000 (Box 30)
  - AER Rejects, M, 2000 (Box 31)
  - AER Rejects, M-N, 2000 (Box 32)
  - AER Rejects, N-P, 2000 (Box 33)
  - AER Rejects, P, 2000 (Box 34)
  - AER Rejects, P-R, 2000 (Box 35)
  - AER Rejects, R-S, 2000 (Box 36)
  - AER Rejects, S, 2000 (Box 37-39)
  - AER Rejects, S-T, 2000 (Box 40)
  - AER Rejects, T-W, 2000 (Box 41)
  - AER Rejects, W, 2000 (Box 42)
  - AER Rejects, W-Z, 2000 (Box 43)
  - AER Rejects, Z, 2000 (Box 44)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (Box 44)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (Box 44)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (Box 44)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 45)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.) (Box 45)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.) (Box 45)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 46)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.) (Box 46)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.) (Box 46)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.) (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.) (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December (cont.) (Box 48)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March (cont.) (Box 48)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December (cont.) (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March (cont.) (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 June (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 September (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 December (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 June (Box 50-52)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 September (Box 50-52)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 December (Box 50-52)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2000 (Box 53)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2000 (cont.) (Box 54)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2001 (cont.) (Box 56)
- Accession (2003-0250), 42 boxes
  Addition (2003-0250) (15750 items, 25.2 lin. ft.; dated 1996-2002) is closed to researchers. Collection contains records for the American Economic Review, including editorial correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts for rejected articles (primarily 2001 and 2002) and accepted articles (2002).
  Written permission from the American Economics Association is required for 50 years. Please see Research Services with questions.
- Accession (2004-0007), 18 boxes
  Addition (2004-0007) (5250 items, 10.8 lin. ft.; dated 1950-2002) consists of general and committee files from the AEA administrative office; Elton Hinshaw's files as the association's secretary-treasurer (ca. 1983-late 1990s); printed programs for annual meetings (1950-2001); agendas and supporting documents for executive committee meetings (ca. 1992-1997); and a 2002 membership directory (in print and on CD-Rom). Also includes files on the Committee on Graduate Education (ca. 1988-1991) and the Committee on the Status of Minority Groups (ca. 1986-2001).
- Accession (2004-0039), 11 boxes
  Addition (2004-0039) (4125 items; 6.6 lin. ft.; dated 2001) consists of files of rejected articles (2001) from the American Economic Review, including correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts.
- Accession (2004-0092), 8 boxes
  Addition (2004-0092) (3000 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 2001-2003) contains files for accepted articles for 2003 issues of the American Economic Review, including the May 2003 Papers and Proceedings. Files contain typescripts of articles, correspondence, and referees' reports.
- Accession (2004-0132), 1 boxes
  Addition (2004-0132) (3 items, 0.4 lin. ft.; dated 2003) consists of a printed copy (3 vols.) of the 2003 AEA membership directory.
- Accession (2004-0316), 57 boxes
  Addition (2004-0316) (21375 items; 34.2 lin. ft.; dated 1993-2004) consists of journal records for the American Economic Review, 1993-2004, including correspondence and referee files for rejected and withdrawn articles, accepted articles, and papers and proceedings.
- Accession (2005-0069), 0 boxes
  Addition (2005-0069) (5 items; .1 lin. ft.; dated 2004-2005) comprises a CD-R containing five electronic files for the 2004 membership directory (3 electronic files saved in different formats). Copies of the electronic documents have been transferred to the electronic records server.
- Accession (2006-0053), 10 boxes
  Addition (2006-0053) (3,750 items, 6 lin. ft.; dated 1980-2000) includes records of the AEA Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), primarily 1996-2000, including correspondence of the chair, annual reports, minutes of the Board, rosters, and files relating to CSWEP newsletters and program sessions at AEA meetings.
- Accession (2006-0066), 60 boxes
  Addition (2006-0066) (22,025 items, 35.6 lin. ft.; dated 1962-1966, 1995-2005) features records for the American Economic Review, including correspondence and referee reports regarding papers rejected for publication, primarily 2001-2004. Also includes Local Arrangements Reports for conventions of the Allied Social Science Association, 1962-1966.
- Accession (2007-0084 and 2007-0085), 17 boxes
  Additions (2007-0084 and 2007-0085) (7500 items, 10.0 lin. ft.; dated 2004-2006) contain records for the American Economic Review, including drafts, correspondence, and referee reports for articles dated 2004-2006. Also included is the AEA member directory for 2006.
- Accession (2007-0089 and 2007-0090), 90 boxes
  Additions (2007-0089 and 2007-0090) (2500 items, 3.4 lin. ft.; dated 1994-2003) contain records for the Journal of Economic Literature, and primarily includes referee reports and correspondence related to accepted articles dated 1994-2003.
- Accession (2008-0066), 1 boxes
  Addition (08-066) (8 items, .6 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2007) comprises membership directories for those years. Includes two CDR's.
- Accession (2008-0239), 6 boxes
  Addition (2008-0239) (2250 items; 3.6 lin. ft.; dated 2008) contains records for the American Economic Review, including drafts, correspondence, and referee reports for articles submitted for publication for vol. 98, issues 1-4 (March-Sept. 2008).
- Accession (2008-0269), 2 boxes
  Addition (2008-0269) (1575 items; 2.1 lin. ft.; dated 2005) contains records for the Journal of Economic Literature, including referee reports and drafts of accepted articles for issues in 2005.
  - Journal of Economic Literature, June 2005 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, March 2005 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, September 2005 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, September 2005 (Box 2)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, December 2005 (Box 2)
- Accession (2009-0204), 7 boxes
  Addition (09-204) (7875 items; 10.5 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2008) includes files for the American Economic Review, volumes 96(2), 97(2), 97(4), 97(5), 98(2) and 98(5).
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 96(2), May 2006 (Box 1-2)
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 97(2), May 2007 (Box 3)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 97(4), September 2007 (Box 4)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 97(5), December 2007 (Box 5)
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 98(2), May 2008 (Box 6)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 98(5), December 2008 (Box 7)
- Accession (2011-0083), 4 boxes
  Addition (2011-0083) (3525 items; 4.7 lin. ft.; dated 2005-2006) contains files for the Journal of Economic Perspectives, including unsolicited papers and proposals; e-mail correspondence; and article drafts and revisions. Not all unsolicited papers and proposals received by the JEP during these years are included; only those of some interest have been saved (for instance, if the author of the paper was particularly notable.) The bulk of the material consists of articles and proposals from 2005 and 2006, the last years before the JEP began publishing and archiving electronically. A few folders pertain to articles published after 2006. These are articles that were began before the JEP's switch to electronic, and thus some of their early files are archived on paper rather than electronically.
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives Proposal List 2005, 57 folders (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives Proposal List 2006, 20 folders (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2005 issue, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2005 issue, 32 folders (Box 1-2)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2005 issue, 27 folders (Box 2-3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2006 issue, 15 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2006 issue, 14 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Fall 2006 issue, 12 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2007 issue, 12 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2007 issue, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2007 issue, 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Fall 2007 issue, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2008 issue, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2008 issue, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2008 issue, 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2009 issue, 1 folder (Box 4)
- Accession (2012-0077), 1995-1998, 3 boxes
  Addition (2012-0077) (4.5 lin. ft.; 3375 items; dated 1995-1998) contains files from the Journal of Economic Literature during the editorship of John Pencavel.
  - JEL files, 1995-1998 (Box 1-3)